{"tossups": [{"question": "This man dispatched dragoons to kidnap the Duc d\u2019Enghien [\u201cduke\u201d den-gh\u2019yen]. This man, who was prohibited from joining the army due to a foot injury in his youth, was removed from one of his posts after embracing the notorious Civil Constitution of the Clergy. This one-time Bishop of Autun demanded bribes of American diplomats in 1797. For ten points, name this French diplomat who represented France during the Congress of Vienna and instigated the XYZ Affair.", "answer": "Charles-Maurice de<b> Talleyrand</b> Perigord", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This president signed the Matthew Shepard Hate Crimes Prevention Act, which expanded the 1969 federal hate-crimes law and required the FBI to track statistics on hate crimes on the basis of gender. Other major statutes passed under this president include the Ledbetter Fair Pay Act and a repeal of the Don\u2019t Ask, Don\u2019t Tell policy. This president issued the DACA and DAPA executive orders on immigration and enacted the Dodd-Frank Act. For ten points, name this president, after whom the Affordable Care Act was nicknamed.", "answer": "Barack<b> Obama</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The<em> Georgios Averof</em> managed to perform this action during the Battle of Elli. This devastating feat was most recently carried out by Jesse Oldendorf against the enemy line during the Battle of Surigao Strait. Zinovy Rozhestvensky was decisively defeated by a performance of this action that relied on wireless telegraphy to coordinate Admiral Togo\u2019s orders. During the Battle of Tsushima Strait, the Japanese fleet was twice able to pull off, for ten points, what now-obsolete naval maneuver, performed by traveling perpendicular to a line of enemy ships?", "answer": "<b> crossing the T</b> (or<b> capping the T</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This woman served as the first president of the New England Woman Suffrage Association, and her husband Samuel was a member of the Secret Six. A pacifist Mother\u2019s Day Proclamation was issued by this woman, who wrote a work that describes a figure who \u201cloosed the fateful lightning of His terrible swift sword;\u201d that work adopted the melody used in \u201cJohn Brown\u2019s Body\u201d and repeats the line \u201cglory, glory, hallelujah!\u201d For ten points, name this lyricist of the \u201cBattle Hymn of the Republic.\u201d", "answer": "Julia Ward<b> Howe</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A ruler of this country formally became its king at the Congress of Lutsk, but died before the crown could physically reach him. A leader of this country defeated Skirgaila before signing the Astrava treaty with Jogaila, allowing him to replace Skirgaila as regent of this country. Vytautas ruled this country, which joined with its southwestern neighbor in the Union of Krewo and the Union of Lublin. For ten points, name this Grand Duchy that formed a commonwealth with Poland.", "answer": "Grand Duchy of<b> Lithuania</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The European Medical Agency was placed in this city in 1995, along with the European Banking Authority in 2011. This city\u2019s Docklands area was revitalized in the 1980s, and its Canary Wharf has since become a major financial center, alongside its more traditional City. Ken Livingstone became this metropolis\u2019s first elected mayor in 2000 and promised reforms including \u201cbendy\u201d buses to replace its iconic two-story buses. For ten points, name this economic center of Britain.", "answer": "<b> London</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "The Fazal Ali commission was created by this man to reorganize states. This man used the Forward Policy to fight China over the Line of Actual Control. V. K. Menon served as this man\u2019s secretary of defense before resigning after the 1962 Sino-Indian War. In one speech, this man declared \u201cthe light has gone out of our lives\u201d after the assassination of his mentor; in another speech, he discussed a \u201cTryst with Destiny.\u201d Indira Gandhi was the daughter of, for ten points, what first prime minister of India?", "answer": "Jawarhalal<b> Nehru</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A close confidant of this tsar was a liberal reformer named Mikhail Speransky. This tsar\u2019s forces were commanded by Levin August von Bennigsen at the Battle of Eylau. This tsar rose to power after the assassination of his predecessor, Paul I. Supporters advocating for the succession of this man\u2019s brother Constantine led a revolt in Saint Petersburg after this man\u2019s death in 1825. The Treaties of Tilsit were signed during the reign of, for ten points, what early nineteenth century tsar who clashed with Napoleon?", "answer": "<b> Alexander I</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In a play that mocks this war, a farmer disguises his daughters as pigs and trades them for salt, while the main character holds a basket of charcoal hostage while trying to argue for an end to this war. In another play, a man flies a dung beetle to heaven to argue for an end to this war. A cause of this war was an embargo against the colony of Megara, as related in the play<em> The Acharnians</em>. Aristophanes\u2019s comedy <em>Peace</em> satirizes the motives of general Cleon\u2019s actions in, for ten points, what war between Athens and Sparta?", "answer": "<b> Peloponnesian</b> War", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Drama"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This function is applied to initial mass over final mass in an equation published in 1903 by Konstantin Tsiolkovsky for the behavior of rockets. Leibniz introduced the modern notation for this function and related it to the integral of 1 over x. This function was discovered and popularized by John Napier, and Henry Briggs compiled a table of these functions and changed them into base 10. For ten points, name this function whose \u201cnatural\u201d example uses<em> e</em> as its base, the inverse of the exponential function.", "answer": "(natural)<b> log</b>arithm", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {}, {"question": "During this conflict, the Ariovistus-led Suebi tribe was defeated. Diviciacus [DIV-ik-ee-ah-kus] warned one side of a conspiracy before these wars, though his people, the Aedui [aid-wee], later flipped allegiances. The losing side in this war did not burn Gergovia or Avaricum, despite a scorched earth strategy, and the winning side built bridges over the Rhine, then burned them as a show of force. In the crucial battle of this war, a double wall was built around Vercingetorix\u2019s forces in Alesia. For ten points, name this set of wars that allowed Julius Caesar to subjugate modern-day France.", "answer": "<b> Gallic</b> Wars (accept descriptions of war(s) between the<b> Gaul</b>s and the Romans)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Dave Paulson was questioned for his role in this event after his business card was left in a police car with a suspicious note on it. Twelve years prior to this event, a group called The</b> <b>Covenant, the Sword, and the Arm of the Lord planned a rocket (+)</b> <b>attack on the same</b> <b>target. Missing license plates prompted Charlie Hanger to arrest the perpetrator of this event, who was inspired to commit it after the (*)</b> ATF siege of the Branch Davidian compound at Waco. Terry Nichols and Timothy McVeigh carried out, for ten points, what 1968 attack on the Alfred P. Murrah Building?", "answer": "<b> Oklahoma City</b> bombing", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A self-portrait done as one of this author\u2019s characters includes a portrait of the painter Emile Bernard in the background and was dedicated to van Gogh, who called it \u201cill and tormented.\u201d A nude sculpture for this man\u2019s memorial shows him beneath waves off the isle of (+) Guernsey. While in exile for his Republican views, this man wrote pamphlets against</b> <b>Napoleon III and a novel that includes a lengthy description of (*)</b> Waterloo. Paul Gauguin painted himself as one of this man\u2019s creations, the convict Jean Valjean. For ten points, name this French author of<em> Les Miserables</em>.", "answer": "Victor Marie<b> Hugo</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>During this man\u2019s premiership, Alexei Larionov tripled production of meat in his native oblast during the Ryazan Miracle. A desire to \u201cshow the United States a Kuzma\u2019s mother\u201d</b> <b>prompted researchers to carry out a (+)</b> <b>nuclear test on Novaya Zemlya. This man only</b> <b>nuclear test on Novaya Zemlya. This man only</b> <b>showed interest in the cafeteria during a visit to (*)</b> <b>showed interest in the cafeteria during a visit to (*)</b> IBM headquarters. The most powerful explosion on Earth, the Tsar Bomba test, was carried out at the beginning of the premiership of, for ten points, what Soviet premier who visited the United States six years after succeeding Stalin?", "answer": "Nikita<b> Khrushchev</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>A symbolic defeat for this religion occurred when the \u201cbora winds\u201d redirected one side\u2019s arrows back at the archers during the Battle of the Frigid River. Members of this religion,</b> <b>who twice had their \u201cAltar of (+)</b> <b>Victory\u201d desecrated, faced new restrictions after the</b> <b>Theodosian Decrees were issued. As the last (*)</b> emperor to follow this religion, Julian was known as the Apostate. This religion was overshadowed by a monotheistic faith after the Edict of Milan. For ten points, name this ancient religion that, before it was supplanted by Christianity, officially honored Janus, Jupiter, and Mars.", "answer": "traditional<b> Roman</b> religion (accept equivalents related to Greco-<b>Roman</b> religion; prompt on paganism; do not accept or prompt on Greek religion alone)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>In 1984, a snap election in this country became known as the \u201cschnapps election\u201d due to the drinking habits of the ousted Prime Minister. In this country, Alain Mafart was part</b> <b>of a team that planted a bomb that killed photographer Fernando Pereira; (+)</b> <b>French</b> <b>Defense Minister Charles Hernu resigned as a result of that action. Prime Minister David Lange instituted (*)</b> Rogernomics in this country, where Greenpeace docked the ship<em> Rainbow Warrior</em> before its bombing in 1985. For ten points, name this country where Robert Muldoon once served as Prime Minister in its capital Wellington.", "answer": "<b> New Zealand</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}